GIULIA MALINVERNO

Senior Application Engineer

INFO AND CONTACT

24/12/1993 Verbania, (VB)

+39 3486985770

giulia.malinverno@ansys.com giulymali93@gmail.com LinkedIn

SKILLS

Agile Programming skills REST API DevOps GitHub

LANGUAGES

Italian English Spanish

EDUCATION

2015-2017

Msc Electrical Engineering @ Università degli studi di Pavia (IT)

Thesis: Study and modelling of a car door drive operator for Schindler's elevators @Schindler Elettronica SA (CH)

2012-2015

Bsc Industttrial Engineering –
Energy Engineering @
Università degli studi di Pavia
(IT)
Thesis: Study of OFIMA's
Hydroelectric pumping
system @OFIMA SA (CH)

PROFILE

Senior application engineer, utilizing my 7+ years of experience in the software industry. Developing workflows to easily automate and overcome the burden of manual operation. Writing codes that are reliable and user-friendly with the aim of scalability. Passionate about everything involving software development, DevOps and technology.

EXPERIENCE

2024-present: Senior Application Engineer @Ansys, Inc.

- #PyAEDT and AEDT Python #toolkits maintener and developer for Low Frequency applications.
- #PyAnsys framework to automate and boost Ansys products
- Agile methodology (Scrum)
- Programming languages: Python.
- Techincal skills: Web services, grpc, RESTAPI, Automated API testing technique (Postman), Interface description language such as Swagger.
- Rest API Python Frameworks: Flask, Bottle.
- CI/CD pipelines, GitHub Actions and Azure Devops
- GitHub & Git

2022-2024: Application Engineer II @Ansys, Inc. 2020-2022: Application Engineer @Ansys, Inc.

2017-2020: Research Engineer @Motor Design Ltd – Wrexham (UK)

- Motor-CAD
- Matlab/Simulink and Matlab scripting.
- ANSYS Maxwell for electric motor applications.
- Programming languages: Vbs, C++, Python

RELEVANT PROJECTS:

- PyAEDT: Pyhton wrapper for Ansys Electronics Desktop @ https://github.com/ansys/pyaedt
- magnet-segmentation-toolkit: Python toolkit to seamlessly automate rotor and magnets segmentation in electric motors application. @ https://github.com/ansys/magnet-segmentation-toolkit
- pyaedt-toolkits-common: Library for creating Ansys Electronics

 Desktop toolkits. @ https://github.com/ansys/pyaedt-toolkits-common